<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on Homechart</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on Homechart</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.homechart.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/android/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/android/</guid><description>Android # Download the app on the Play Store to get started with Homechart on Android.
Connecting to Self-Hosted Instances # Tick the &amp;ldquo;Self-Hosted Server&amp;rdquo; button on the Sign In or Sign Up page to connect to your self-hosted instance. Fill in the address of your self-hosted instance (e.g. https://web.homechart.app).
Homechart on Android is actually the web version, just repackaged as something called a Trusted Web Activity. Our household uses Android devices, so Android receives a lot of &amp;ldquo;extended testing&amp;rdquo; by us.</description></item><item><title>In The Cloud (Hosted)</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/in-the-cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/in-the-cloud/</guid><description> In The Cloud (Hosted) # Visit https://web.homechart.app/signup and signup for a new account to start using Homechart in the cloud.
Our household uses Homechart Cloud!</description></item><item><title>Requirements</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/requirements/</guid><description>Requirements # 1. Server # The server component of Homechart is written in Go and has very low resource requirements:
1 CPU 512MB RAM 2. Database # Homechart requires full access to a PostgreSQL 14 database. Older or newer versions may work, but they are not tested.
You can create a database for Homechart on an existing PostgreSQL server with these commands, replacing the database name, username and password:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/binary-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/binary-install/</guid><description>Binary Install # Homechart can be deployed as a standalone binary on Linux (amd64 and arm) from our releases website.
1. Review the requirements # Ensure your system meets the Server Requirements.
2. Download Homechart # Visit https://releases.homechart.app/ and download the version of Homechart for your platform. Optionally, you can verify your download by comparing the SHA-512 sum:
$ sha256sum -c homechart_latest_linux_amd64.gz.sha256 Once your download has completed, decompress it:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/container-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/container-install/</guid><description>Container Install # Homechart can be deployed as a container on Linux (amd64 and arm) from our images hosted on GitHub.
1. Review the requirements # Ensure your system meets the Server Requirements.
2. Install a container runtime # Homechart can run on any OCI compatible runtime on Linux amd64 and arm64. Most users use Docker and Docker Compose, but we also support Kubernetes and Podman.
3. Run Homechart # The Homechart container is configured to start Homechart server without having to specify a command or entrypoint.</description></item><item><title>iOS</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/ios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/ios/</guid><description>iOS # Download the app on the App Store to get started with Homechart on iOS.
Connecting to Self-Hosted Instances # Tick the &amp;ldquo;Self-Hosted Server&amp;rdquo; button on the Sign In or Sign Up page to connect to your self-hosted instance. Fill in the address of your self-hosted instance (e.g. https://web.homechart.app).
The iOS version of Homechart is a repackaging of the web version using a tool called Capacitor. This repackaging has caused some problems in the past, and we do occasionally run into iOS specific bugs.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/getting-help/community-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/getting-help/community-support/</guid><description>Community Support # Homechart communities are available to help with common issues encountered with self-hosting and advice for using Homechart on different devices.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/getting-help/paid-support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/getting-help/paid-support/</guid><description>Paid Support # After setting up your Homechart subscription, you can use the Contact Us options in the menu to submit support and feature requests.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/communities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/communities/</guid><description> Communities # Join our user communities to give and receive help!
Discord GitHub Reddit</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/documentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/documentation/</guid><description>Documentation # Documenting Homechart is an ongoing effort. Please contact us or update the documentation yourself if you feel something is missing!
Updating Documentation # You can update our documentation if you feel something is missing. Checkout this git repo and open a pull request with your changes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/translating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/helping-out/translating/</guid><description>Translations # Translating Homechart is an ongoing process. You can help us out by updating or adding translations or contacting support with the language you want or corrected translations.
Updating or Adding Translations # Homechart generates translations from the translations.yaml file. It&amp;rsquo;s a big file, but it lets you see everything there is to translate in Homechart.
Syntax # The syntax for the file is easy to understand:
defaultcode: en # English is the default/fallback language iso639codes: # A list of the ISO-639 codes and the display name for them de: Deutsch en: English translations: # A list of translation objects.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/client/web/</guid><description>Web # Homechart can be used by any web browser. Visit https://web.homechart.app or your self-hosted URL to get started. On compatible devices, Homechart will prompt you to install it&amp;ndash;this will install Homechart as if it is a native app.
Homechart uses a lot of neat web technologies to be as close to a native app as possible. We spend a lot of time ensuring it&amp;rsquo;s fast, doesn&amp;rsquo;t slow down your device, and feels responsive and snappy.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/configuration-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/configuration-options/</guid><description>Configuration Options # Homechart can be configured using environment variables or a JSON configuration file. The configuration is divided into sections:
App App PostgreSQL SMTP Vault Web Push For environment variables, every configuration key can be set using HOMECHART_&amp;lt;SECTION&amp;gt;_&amp;lt;KEY&amp;gt;=a value, i.e. HOMECHART_CLI_DEBUG=true
For a JSON or YAML configuration file, the keys are camelCase and nested under each section:
JSON
{ &amp;#34;app&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;baseURL&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;example.com&amp;#34; } } YAML
app: baseURL: example.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/backups/</guid><description>Backups # Please remember to backup your data! Self-hosted Homechart is easy to backup: all persistent data is stored in PostgreSQL, Homechart doesn&amp;rsquo;t save anything locally. You can use tools like pg_dump or wal-g to perform the backup.
Additionally, you can have your self-hosted instance perform automated, encrypted backups to Homechart Cloud. Visit /subscription on your self-hosted instance to enable this.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/households/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/households/</guid><description>Households # Using households in Homechart requires a subscription, even for self-hosted users. You can subscribe monthly or yearly , or buy a lifetime subscription/one time purchase, too.
Linking Your Household to Homechart Cloud # You&amp;rsquo;ll need to link your self-hosted instance household to a household on Homechart Cloud to use your subscription. No data is transferred to Homechart Cloud, it&amp;rsquo;s just used to transfer the subscription details.
Sign up for a new account on Homechart Cloud On Homechart Cloud, create a household and setup a subscription (either during setup or under https://web.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/updates/</guid><description>Updates # Homechart is easily updated by replacing the container or executable with a newer version.
Binary Updates # Download a new copy of homechart_latest to install or update Homechart. You can compare the SHA-512 sum of your existing executable to see if you need to update. See Binary Install, it&amp;rsquo;s the same process as installing.
Container Updates # Pull the latest container to update Homechart, e.g.:
$ docker pull candiddev/homechart:latest Depending on how you&amp;rsquo;re running Homechart, you may need to remove the existing Homechart container or re-run docker-compose up</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/security/client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/security/client/</guid><description>Client Security # Homechart&amp;rsquo;s Android, iOS, and Web clients are developed using TypeScript and standard web development tooling. Here are some of the methods we use to help keep Homechart&amp;rsquo;s client code free of vulnerabilities:
Limit Third-Party Libraries: We try and use as few third-party libraries as possible, and when we do select a third-party library, we review the codebase to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s something we are comfortable maintaining. No Cookies: We do not use cookies for client-side authentication and authorization.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/security/server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/security/server/</guid><description>Server Security # Homechart&amp;rsquo;s Cloud and Self-Hosted server is developed using Go. Here are some of the methods we use to help keep Homechart&amp;rsquo;s server code free of vulnerabilities:
Argon2 Password Hashing: We hash user passwords with Argon2. Auth Test Suite: We use an extensive authentication and authorization test suite for every pull request and build. Limit Third-Party Libraries: We try and use as few third-party libraries as possible, and when we do select a third-party library, we review the codebase to ensure it&amp;rsquo;s something we are comfortable maintaining.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/bookmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/bookmarks/</guid><description>Bookmarks # Bookmarks help you manage links to other apps and services. You can create personal or household bookmarks, show and hide Bookmarks in the Home and Menu, and control how the Bookmark apps open within Homechart.
Our household uses Bookmarks to share/access links to self-hosted services like Home Assistant.
I added Bookmarks to Homechart to replace a Google Sheet we used for sharing/remembering links.
Use Image for Icon # You can have an image like a favicon or the logo for the app be displayed instead of an icon for Bookmarks.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/budget/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/budget/</guid><description>Budget # Budget helps you manage and save your money.
Our household uses Budget for all of our finances. We have Accounts for our financial institutions, as well as Accounts for assets like our vehicles.
For Categories, we split our bills into two Groupings &amp;ndash; monthly bills, with Categories for Cellphone, Electricity, etc. We have another grouping for Non-Monthly bills, like Property Taxes. We also have Entertainment categories for each household member&amp;ndash;we put our kid&amp;rsquo;s allowance in them (we call it The I Owe You Bank).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/calendar/</guid><description>Calendar # Calendar helps you see everything going on in your Household.
Our household uses Calendar for everything. We track all of our household activities in it, and we use the color functionality extensively&amp;ndash;my wife migrated from a physical, dry-erase calendar on our fridge to Homechart. Now we almost never forget anything, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see who is taking care of what.
Seeing Calendar come alive in Homechart was really neat.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/cook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/cook/</guid><description>Cook # Cook helps you organize your recipes and create meal plans.
Our household uses Cook for all of our meal plans. We have over 300 recipes, and we try to cook most of our dinners at home. We try to get the kids to help pick out meals, but most of our meal planning involves hitting the Surprise Me button until something sounds good. We take turns cooking meals using the Chef option to limit the amount of cooking we have to do individually.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/health/</guid><description>Health # Health helps you and your family log the way you feel, the food you eat, and the symptoms you have to help you discover correlations between your health and your environment. Health is great for tracking your own health, but you and your spouse can use it to track your child&amp;rsquo;s health, too. In a household, Household Owners can manage a child&amp;rsquo;s health data, but they can&amp;rsquo;t see each other&amp;rsquo;s data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/inventory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/inventory/</guid><description>Inventory # Inventory helps you track and organize things in your household. You can use Inventory to track big purchases, warranties, items in your pantry, storage bins, and more.
Our household uses Inventory extensively. We have storage bins in our basement filled with old clothes, decorations, and other supplies that live in Homechart as Collections. We converted a Google Sheet containing our Big Purchases, computer builds, and warranties into Inventory Items, and I track all of my Z-Wave devices in it and note when I change their batteries.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/notes/</guid><description>Notes # Notes help you organize and manage your household knowledgebase and wiki.
Our household uses Notes as a way to remember things, like how to use the generator in case of a blackout or important phone numbers/contacts for babysitters.
I added Notes to Homechart as a way to centralize a bunch of Google Docs. I wanted a household wiki without having to spin up any of the various wiki solutions, and I wanted to be able to reference things without have to copy/paste links everywhere.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/plan/</guid><description>Plan # Plan helps you track personal and household Projects and Tasks in one spot.
Our household uses Plan to track recurring household tasks and household projects. We have recurring tasks for chores (for everyone in the household, kids included), maintenance reminders, and our pets. We track all of our household projects/vacations/home improvement plans within it so we all know what needs to be done.
I added Plan to Homechart to replace Todoist for our household.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/reward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/reward/</guid><description>Reward # Reward helps your household do positive reinforcement.
Our household uses Reward to help our kids work on good behaviors. We create cards with goals we want our kids to achieve and tie the reward to something they want like screen time.
I added Reward to Homechart when my wife read about creating punch cards for positive reinforcement.
Cards # Reward &amp;gt; Cards represent tasks that need to completed a certain number of times to receive a reward.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/secrets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/secrets/</guid><description>Secrets # Secrets help you protect notes, information, and other household data.
Our household uses Secrets for storing and sharing passwords/as a password manager. Whenever we sign up for a new website, we generate a password and save the credentials in Homechart.
I added Secrets because Homechart needs a way to keep things completely confidential so only the person or household has access to them. I modeled it after Bitwarden, which my household was using previously, but I wanted it to offer a more flexible method for securing values.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/shop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/shop/</guid><description>Shop # Shop helps you organize your shopping, grocery, and wish lists.
Our household uses Shop for grocery and general household supplies. After creating our Meal Plan for the week, we add all of the ingredients that aren&amp;rsquo;t in our Inventory to our shopping list. Anytime we are low on something, we add it to Homechart, and for things we use regularly like bread, we create Staples for them. For our Household Projects, we track materials we need like paint, wood, or parts that we need to buy.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/platform/markdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/platform/markdown/</guid><description>Markdown # You can use Markdown to format text within Homechart. Using Markdown, you can turn things into links, make text bold/italic, creating lists, and more. Here is an overview of the basic Markdown syntax.
Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of Markdown! It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to use, and most things that use Markdown in Homechart have a Preview button so you can view what it looks like before you save. Linking Within Homechart # Homechart can reference various things inside Homechart using Markdown.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/platform/settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/platform/settings/</guid><description>Settings # Settings are where you manage all of the various controls for Homechart.
Account # Settings &amp;gt; Account has controls for adjusting your Preferences, Components, and Security.
Preferences # You can adjust your account Name, Language, Date, and Time, and Color and Theme under Preferences. Your account Name will be visible to all members of your Household.
Hide Components # Using the controls on this page, you can hide various components within Homechart.</description></item><item><title>Single Sign-On (SSO)</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/sso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/operations/sso/</guid><description>Single Sign-On (SSO) # For self-hosted users, Homechart can integrate with your existing authentication system to allow your household members to authenticate with it or even sign in automatically. Some things to note:
The account will be created if the email address does not exist in Homechart already. You should pre-create your household members using the email address that the SSO will pass through, otherwise they will be created under a separate household.</description></item><item><title>unRAID</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/platform_specific/unraid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/installing-homechart/server/on-your-network/installation/platform_specific/unraid/</guid><description> unRAID # Homechart works well on unRAID Servers, but some users frequently encounter issues getting Homechart and PostgreSQL to talk to each other. Here are some tips from our users on getting this working:
Ensure you&amp;rsquo;re using Docker Set the environment variable HOMECHART_POSTGRESQL_HOSTNAME to the correct hostname or IP address of your PostgreSQL container (make sure to reserve the IP)</description></item></channel></rss>