<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homechart</title><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/</link><description>Recent content on Homechart</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/bookmarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/bookmarks/</guid><description>Bookmarks # Bookmarks help you manage links to other apps and services. You can create personal or household bookmarks, show and hide Bookmarks in the Home and Menu, and control how the Bookmark apps open within Homechart.
Our household uses Bookmarks to share/access links to self-hosted services like Home Assistant.
I added Bookmarks to Homechart to replace a Google Sheet we used for sharing/remembering links.
Use Image for Icon # You can have an image like a favicon or the logo for the app be displayed instead of an icon for Bookmarks.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/budget/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/budget/</guid><description>Budget # Budget helps you manage and save your money.
Our household uses Budget for all of our finances. We have Accounts for our financial institutions, as well as Accounts for assets like our vehicles.
For Categories, we split our bills into two Groupings &amp;ndash; monthly bills, with Categories for Cellphone, Electricity, etc. We have another grouping for Non-Monthly bills, like Property Taxes. We also have Entertainment categories for each household member&amp;ndash;we put our kid&amp;rsquo;s allowance in them (we call it The I Owe You Bank).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/calendar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/calendar/</guid><description>Calendar # Calendar helps you see everything going on in your Household.
Our household uses Calendar for everything. We track all of our household activities in it, and we use the color functionality extensively&amp;ndash;my wife migrated from a physical, dry-erase calendar on our fridge to Homechart. Now we almost never forget anything, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see who is taking care of what.
Seeing Calendar come alive in Homechart was really neat.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/cook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/cook/</guid><description>Cook # Cook helps you organize your recipes and create meal plans.
Our household uses Cook for all of our meal plans. We have over 300 recipes, and we try to cook most of our dinners at home. We try to get the kids to help pick out meals, but most of our meal planning involves hitting the Surprise Me button until something sounds good. We take turns cooking meals using the Chef option to limit the amount of cooking we have to do individually.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/health/</guid><description>Health # Health helps you and your family log the way you feel, the food you eat, and the symptoms you have to help you discover correlations between your health and your environment. Health is great for tracking your own health, but you and your spouse can use it to track your child&amp;rsquo;s health, too. In a household, Household Owners can manage a child&amp;rsquo;s health data, but they can&amp;rsquo;t see each other&amp;rsquo;s data.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/inventory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/inventory/</guid><description>Inventory # Inventory helps you track and organize things in your household. You can use Inventory to track big purchases, warranties, items in your pantry, storage bins, and more.
Our household uses Inventory extensively. We have storage bins in our basement filled with old clothes, decorations, and other supplies that live in Homechart as Collections. We converted a Google Sheet containing our Big Purchases, computer builds, and warranties into Inventory Items, and I track all of my Z-Wave devices in it and note when I change their batteries.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/notes/</guid><description>Notes # Notes help you organize and manage your household knowledgebase and wiki.
Our household uses Notes as a way to remember things, like how to use the generator in case of a blackout or important phone numbers/contacts for babysitters.
I added Notes to Homechart as a way to centralize a bunch of Google Docs. I wanted a household wiki without having to spin up any of the various wiki solutions, and I wanted to be able to reference things without have to copy/paste links everywhere.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/plan/</guid><description>Plan # Plan helps you track personal and household Projects and Tasks in one spot.
Our household uses Plan to track recurring household tasks and household projects. We have recurring tasks for chores (for everyone in the household, kids included), maintenance reminders, and our pets. We track all of our household projects/vacations/home improvement plans within it so we all know what needs to be done.
I added Plan to Homechart to replace Todoist for our household.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/reward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/reward/</guid><description>Reward # Reward helps your household do positive reinforcement.
Our household uses Reward to help our kids work on good behaviors. We create cards with goals we want our kids to achieve and tie the reward to something they want like screen time.
I added Reward to Homechart when my wife read about creating punch cards for positive reinforcement.
Cards # Reward &amp;gt; Cards represent tasks that need to completed a certain number of times to receive a reward.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/secrets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/secrets/</guid><description>Secrets # Secrets help you protect notes, information, and other household data.
Our household uses Secrets for storing and sharing passwords/as a password manager. Whenever we sign up for a new website, we generate a password and save the credentials in Homechart.
I added Secrets because Homechart needs a way to keep things completely confidential so only the person or household has access to them. I modeled it after Bitwarden, which my household was using previously, but I wanted it to offer a more flexible method for securing values.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/shop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.homechart.app/using-homechart/components/shop/</guid><description>Shop # Shop helps you organize your shopping, grocery, and wish lists.
Our household uses Shop for grocery and general household supplies. After creating our Meal Plan for the week, we add all of the ingredients that aren&amp;rsquo;t in our Inventory to our shopping list. Anytime we are low on something, we add it to Homechart, and for things we use regularly like bread, we create Staples for them. For our Household Projects, we track materials we need like paint, wood, or parts that we need to buy.</description></item></channel></rss>